DAN KLEIN: OK.
So if you have a completely separated
graph, you have independent
sub-problems.
But you probably don't.
If you have a tree-structured
CSP, then you can
apply this great algorithm.
But guess what?
Your CSP is probably not
tree-structured either.
And so what we'd like for you to do is
take a constraint graph that doesn't
have the structure we want and
improve its structure.
And there's a very simple
way to do this.
So let's imagine we had a nearly
tree-structured CSP.
So for example, on the Australia graph,
it's pretty much a tree or, in
particular, it's pretty much a straight
line, if only Southern
Australia weren't there.
OK.
Well, what are we going to do about
Southern Australia to get rid of it?
Well, we have this technique
called conditioning.
And that is Southern Australia
is going to still be there.
Don't worry.
But we're going to assign
a value to it.
Once we've assigned a value to it and
we imagine that that value that we
assign to SA is fixed, then the rest
of the graph can forget that that
variable exists.
Any constraint that existed on an arc
touching SA can now turn into a unary
constraint on the other end.
OK.
So if we assign SA red, this constraint
says, essentially, that WA
can't be red.
So we can remove SA from the graph
and add a unary constraint in
its place on WA.
So we get a simpler graph, once we
instantiate SA and then remove it.
So the algorithm we have for making
something that is nearly
tree-structured into a tree-structure
is called cutset conditioning.
It says, find a set of variables,
hopefully, a very small set of
variables, that, when instantiated
and removed from the graph,
leave you with a tree.
And of course, this idea could also
leave you with independent sub-graphs.
That would be fine too.
If your cutset is of size C, then you
might have to try all possible
instantiations of the cutset.
So you're still going to be exponential
in the size of your
cutset, but you're going to
be linear in the size of
everything that's left over.
So if you have a small cutset, it means
you're close to being a tree.
You instantiate that cutset,
possibly, many times.
And now you're on your fast algorithm.
The whole cutset conditioning algorithm
looks something like this.
You take your graph.
You choose a cutset.
You're going to instantiate that
cutset in all possible ways.
Maybe you'll luck out and not
have to try them all.
So here are all the ways you can
instantiate that cutset.
For each instantiation, you compute the
residual CSP by removing the nodes
that are instantiated and replacing
their constraints with smaller
constraints over the remaining
variables.
So once you have a simplified version
of the constraint graph, you can now
apply a simpler algorithm like the
tree-structured algorithm.
Is it hard to find what the cutset is?
Finding smallest cutset, NP-hard.
Anything you want to do, NP-hard.
Sorry, this is an AI class.
Everything is hard.
Sometimes you know something
that lets you find it for
your particular problem.
Sometimes you can find a small one.
Very small cutsets aren't that hard to
find, because you can just search all
the possibilities.
But if a cutset's kind of a moderate
size, it can be very difficult to find
the best one.